Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/patricia-scott (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Workflow Analysis
Staff Development
Customer Relations

Certifications CEN

Patricia Scott

Injury Prevention and Trauma Outreach Education Coordinator for Trauma Services at Delray Medical Center

Stuart, Florida

Summary

Clinical expertise with emergency, trauma, and obstetrical nursing practiced in community and tertiary facilities with promotion to management positions including experience with senior leadership at Chief Nursing Officer level.

Areas of expertise: ED/Critical Care/Women's Services nursing; Education for healthcare providers(EMS and Nursing);Metric gains/ LEAN experience /charge capture/quality/patient experience /staff satisfaction

Experience

Delray Medical Center
Injury Prevention and Trauma Outreach Coordinator
February 2019 - Present (1 year 6 months)
Delray Beach, FL

Emergency Medical Consultants, Inc Faculty Member March 2002 - Present (18 years 5 months) Port St. Lucie, Florida

Duke LifePoint Sovah Danville Interim Director Emergency Services October 2018 - January 2019 (4 months) Danville, Virginia

Interim administrative assignment in 32 bed ED in Southern Virginia in a Duke LifePoint hospital with 47K ED visits. Assignment is focused on staff stability, throughput, and improving operational processes to improve stroke, sepsis, STEMI care.

Duke LifePoint Wilson Medical Center Interim Director Emergency Services

September 2018 - October 2018 (2 months)

Wilson, North Carolina

Administrative and operational responsibility for 48K visit ED part of Duke LifePoint Healthcare .

Martin Memorial Health Systems
Director Patient Care
June 2016 - March 2018 (1 year 10 months)
Stuart, Florida

Administrative responsibility for Emergency Services operations for Martin South Hospital.

Aurora Health Care
Emergency Services Manager
August 2014 - June 2016 (1 year 11 months)
Aurora Medical Center Kenosha, Wisconsin

Oversight of the Emergency Department including the EMS liaison, SANE program and trauma services for the Kenosha, WI facility.

Columbia St. Mary's Interim Director Critical Care September 2013 - February 2014 (6 months)

Administrative director for Intensive Care Unit, Intermediate Care Unit, and Burn Unit

Bay Medical Sacred Heart Health System Director of Emergency Services, MICU, SICU July 2011 - August 2013 (2 years 2 months)

Administrative and operational accountability for ED with 70K visits and MICU/ SICU intensive care units.

Baptist Healthcare System
Director of Emergency Services
March 2009 - March 2011 (2 years 1 month)
Paducah, KY

Administrative director of Emergency Services for 350 bed regional referral center in Western Kentucky

Florida Hospital DeLand Director of Emergency Services 2006 - 2009 (3 years) Administrative responsibility for ED/ICU for community facility part of Adventist Health System. Interim assignment as CNO during tenure.

Martin Memorial Health Systems ED Director 2002 - 2005 (3 years)

University of KY Chandler Medical Center Staff RN and Division Charge RN 1997 - 2000 (3 years)

Hurley Medical Center Assistant Nurse Manager 1993 - 1997 (4 years)

Education

Nova Southeastern University MBA, business · (2005 - 2006)

University of Michigan BSN, Nursing · (1987 - 1990)